《越狱》第四季 第二十集
Prison.Break.S04E20
《越狱》 前情提要
Previously on prison break.
你准备什么时候告诉我
When were you planning on
你母亲是幕后主使
Telling me that your mother was behind you on this?
你只有今天一天的时间了
You have today, one day.
当布鲁斯把锡拉带回来的时候
When Burrows brings Scylla back to us,
你就是让他脑袋开花的那个人
You will be the one to put a bullet in his brain.
纳文・班纳吉
Naveen banerjee,
是南都・班纳吉总理的儿子
The son of prime minister Nandu Banerjee.
当这一切都过去了
Soon, this will all be behind us,
我可能还有机会见到我的孙子
And maybe I can meet my grandson.
林肯在哪里
Where's Linc?!
现在正在开一个能源会议
There's an energy conference.
在熊猫湾酒店  他会在那里
The Panda Bay Hotel. He'll be there.
克里斯蒂娜的计划
Christina's plan...
她利用锡拉从中渔利所欠的东风
what she needed to profit from Scylla,
就是一种让事态升级为世界大战的催化剂
an incident that'll domino into global warfare.
不要
No!
他们用林肯的名字租了这个
They rented this in Linc's name.
看看这里  这是个陷阱
Look at this. It's a setup!
弹壳上都是他的指纹
His hands are all over the shells.
林肯这回可是竹篮打水一场空了
Lincoln's right back where he started.
这样对迈克尔太残忍了
It really is too bad about Michael.
我们得赶快离开
We gotta go.
我需要医生
I need a doctor here!
他们在那里
There they are!
他们在楼上
They're up there! They're up there!
我们快上楼
Let's go upstairs, now!
快上  上
Move it, move it!
我们混到人群里面吧
Look, let's just blend into the crowd.
我们不能那么出去
No, we can't go that way.
门锁上了  迈克尔
The door is locked, Michael.
退后
Stand back.
这事越来越麻烦了
This whole thing is falling apart.
你觉得呢
Is it?
真的吗
Is it really?
你觉得现在这样很好笑吗
What, do you think this is funny? Huh?
你觉得这事情会多快
How long do you think it's gonna take
传到将军那里去的
Before the general sees this on the news?
如果他觉得我们拿不到锡拉
If he thinks we can't get Scylla,
你觉得他会花多久时间来灭了我们
How long do you think it's gonna take before he comes after us?
我们的家人也将在劫难逃
And then he comes after our families?
确实很搞笑  对吧
Yeah, it's really funny, isn't it?
迈克尔  你在哪
Michael, where are you?
我们还在宾馆里
We're still in the hotel.
有没有其他办法
Is there any other way
出来的时候不被人发现吗
To get out of here without being seen?
没有  到处都是警察和联邦探员
No, there's cops and feds all over the place.
你拿到锡拉了吗
Did you get Scylla?
没有
No.
有人被暗杀了
Some guy got assassinated.
你猜猜谁又被陷害了
And guess who got set up for it.
我们需要锡拉
We need Scylla.
锡拉不见了
Scylla is gone!
我现在只想
The only thing I care about right now
从这里逃出去
Is getting out of here.
是吗  你能往哪儿逃呢  迈克尔
Oh, yeah? Where you gonna go, Michael, huh?
我们会再次陷入公司的穷追猛打中
With the company breathing down our back again.
斯科菲尔德  我是当
Scofield, it's Don.
你想干什么
What do you want?
帮你解决问题
To try to fix this.
怎么解决
How?
又想背后捅我们一刀
By stabbing us in the back again?
让阿历克斯和我说话
Put alex on.
他现在不太好分心
He's a little preoccupied right now.
如果你想冲我发火
Look, you want to be mad at me,
等我们拿到了锡拉再发火也不迟
be mad at me after we get Scylla back.
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
西南边的卸货区有一扇工业门
Okay, the southwest loading dock is a large industrial door.
不是一个快速逃生口
It's not conducive to a quick exit.
只有一个警察把守着
They only have one cop on it.
你们到门口时  我来解决那个警察
When you get to the door, I can incapacitate the cop.
问题是  我们在宾馆的另一边
Problem is, we're on the other side of the hotel,
而他们把一楼封锁了
and they've got the ground floor covered.
你们在外边还看见了什么
What else can you see on the outside?
没了  只有警察
Nothing, just the cop,
垃圾箱  叉车和装换洗衣服的箱子
A couple of dumpsters, jack pallets and some laundry bins.
那就是说宾馆的洗衣房在另一边
That must mean the on-site laundry's on the other side of the hotel,
靠近卸货区大门
Near the loading dock door.
如果我们能到洗衣房  我们就能到大门
If we get to the laundry, we can get to the door.
你说过我们不能到宾馆另一边
You said we can't make it across the hotel.
但是我们可以从屋顶过去
But we can get access to the roof.
宾馆都是用屋顶通风设备
Hotels use rooftop ventilation,
这样  客人才不会闻到洗衣房的味道
So the hotel guests don't smell the laundry fumes.
那好  那就从通风设施那边
Okay, so, listen, take the ventilation system
到洗衣房  如果你们能到洗衣房
To the laundry room. If you can get to the laundry room,
你们就能到大门口
You're gonna get right by the door.
打开免提功能
Put me on speaker.
阿历克斯  你想摆脱公司对我们的纠缠吗
Alex, you want to get the company off our backs?
到邓恩街4号
Go to 4 Dunn place.
莎拉正看着我妈
Sara's holding my mother there.
让她告诉我们锡拉在什么地方
Make her tell us where Scylla is.
还我们一个清白
And clear our names in all this.
马宏  你一定要想尽一切办法撬开她的嘴
Mahone, you need to do whatever you gotta do to get her talk
你明白吗
You hear me?
该怎么做  就怎么做
Do whatever you gotta do.
明白
Got it.
我们走
Come on.
熊猫湾酒店现在是一片混乱
It is complete mayhem at the Panda Bay Hotel
纳文・班纳吉  印度总理的儿子
Where Naveen Banerjee, The son of india's prime minister,
在这里被暗杀了
Has been assassinated.
有趣的是  有小道消息透露
Amazingly, there have been unconfirmed reports
暗杀者正是林肯・布鲁斯
Identifying the assailants as none other than Lincoln Burrows,
杀害泰伦斯・斯坦曼的那个嫌疑犯
the man who'd been suspected of murdering Terrence Steadman,
还有他弟弟兼策划者迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
And Michael Scofield, his mastermind brother...
克里斯蒂娜把我们都给耍了
Christina sandbagged all of us!
如果他们兄弟俩被抓了
If the brothers are caught,
我们就不能保证
We have no control over what
他们会对警察说什么了
They might say to the authorities.
到酒店去
Get down to that hotel
保证他们不会胡说八道
And make sure they don't have that opportunity.
将军  我非常愿意来接手这项行动
Uh, general, I'd be more than willing to take on that assignment.
我保证  我一定会指挥有方的
And I assure you I will dispatch of it efficiently.
泰迪  我们不是在玩捕猎游戏
This is not an alabama coon hunt, Teddy.
别以为我是一时冲动
Don't judge me by desperate actions
刀架在脖子上的日子我都挺过来了
I've taken when there's been a gun to my head.
我领导监狱里的黑帮
I ran an entire prison gang syndicate.
再心狠手辣的罪犯都奉我为上宾
Hardened felons called me "Mister."
我不是一个告密的小人
I'm so much more than a snitch.
如果你以为我只是那样的人
And if you continue to treat me as such,
那就是你的损失  我无所谓  将军阁下
It will be your loss, General, not mine.
孩子  我手里掌握着一家几百万亿
Son, I have the fate of a multi-trillion dollar
资产公司的命运
enterprise in my hands,
你认为现在我会让你大出风头吗
And you want me to let you earn your stripes now?!
摆平那兄弟俩
Take care of the brothers.
应该是这了
This should be it.
好极了
Perfect.
他们说我们的人马上就到
They say ours should be here shortly.
你们要提高警惕
I want you guys on full alert
时刻准备行动  好吗
And get all geared up, all right?
他们在那
It's them!
别动
Stop!
他们会在任何一层楼出现
They could be on any floor.
你能控制所有的门锁吗
Can you override the door locks?
可以  都是电子锁
Yeah, they're electronic.
我们在楼下控制
We control everything from down here.
我要酒店的所有房间门都锁上
I want every room in this hotel locked down now!
我们为什么不走楼梯去天台
Why don't we just take the stairs to the roof?
因为我们将拉响火警
Because we'll set off the fire alarm.
通过顶楼房间上方夹层的管道
The ducts in the crawl spaces above these top floor rooms,
才是我们到天台的通道
That's how we get our rooftop access.
只要我们找到了洗衣房的通风口
Once we find the laundry vent,
我们就从那里到卸货区
We take that down to the loading dock.
门全锁了
That should do it.
出什么事了
What's going on?
他们把我们关在门外了
They locked us out.
我们到不了天台
We can't get to the roof.
那我们往回走下楼去
Let's head back down.
警察会在楼梯井等着我们
There'll be cops in the stairwell.
无论上下  我们都走投无路了
We can't go up, we can't go down...
我们被困住了
We're trapped.
熊猫湾暗杀事件现在有了新的进展
There has been a new development in the Panda Bay assassination.
有匿名消息透露
An anonymous source has provided Fox
有文件显示  布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德
With documents showing a wire transfer
从中国特工处得到了一笔汇款
From Chinese operatives to Burrows and Scofield.
从地理政治角度来看
The fallout from this from a geopolitical standpoint
这件事的负面影响震惊世人
Is staggering.
中国和印度的关系...
Relations between China and India...
南都联系我们了
Nandu reached out.
他想见你
He wants to meet with you.
这事只能这么办了
This couldn't have worked out better.
中方的假文件伪造得不错
Nice audible on the Chinese document.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在  我们只要
Now we just...
静观其变就可以了
Watch the dominoes begin to fall.
我希望他们不要为难迈克尔
I just wish they weren't falling on Michael.
克里斯蒂娜  你给过他活路
Christina, you gave him options,
他走了自己的路  选择和我们干到底
He made his choice, he picked his side.
是的  但他终究是我儿子
Yes, but he is my son.
我唯一的儿子
My only son.
现在  我们相信
And right now it is believed
布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德
Both Burrows and Scofield
仍然在酒店里
Are still in the hotel,
警方正一步步缩小包围圈
But it appears the police are closing in.
熊猫湾酒店  现场报道
Live just outside the Panda Bay Hotel...
不行  迈克尔  这就是问题所在
No, no, no, you see, that's the problem, Michael.
到处都是警察
There's cops everywhere.
就好像是蚂蚁们倾巢出动了一样
It's like a freaking cop anthill out here.
他们找到你们只不过是时间问题
Look, it's just a matter of time till they find you anyway.
搞清楚他们的进攻方案
Find out what their plan of attack is.
好啊  告诉你
Sure, you know what?
我现在就过去问问他们  行了吧
Yeah, I'll just go up and ask them, all right?
他们非常和蔼可亲
They look like a real friendly bunch.
我们没多少时间了  速战速决吧
We don't have much time, so get it done now!
布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德有可能全副武装
Burrows and Scofield could be armed to the teeth.
楼梯的空间很窄
It's tight quarters in the stairwell,
我不想看到枪战  明白吗
So I don't want a lot of shooting, all right?
这家伙是国土安全局的
This guy's from Homeland Security.
我逮捕了枪手之后
I'll file my report as soon as
就会把报告发过去
I've apprehended the shooters.
队长  我希望你搞明白
Whoa, whoa, let me be clear here, captain.
今天的暗杀
The shooting that happened today
不是普通的团伙暴力
Wasn't your typical gangbanger,
迈阿密的破案环境是不是让你退化了
Public service killing you're used to here in Miami.
这是国际性质的暗杀活动
This was an international assassination with ramifications
直接影响了我们国家的安全
That directly affect the security of this country.
如果  你再对我爱理不理的
So, if you turn your back on me again,
我会以妨碍联邦调查让你吃不了兜着走
I'll jam you up for hindering a federal investigation.
你明白吗
You understand?
好吧
Fine.
但是  你要跟在我后面
But I want you on my hip.
我不会让你来转一圈之后
I'm not gonna have you running around playing
让你回去好跟你的朋友吹嘘
So you can go back to your buddies at the office
你经历过真正的枪林弹雨  懂吗
And tell them you saw some real gun play, understood?
没问题
Not a problem.
那你现在告诉我
Now, why don't you start by telling me
你准备怎么解决问题
How you're gonna diffuse the situation?
我们会逐层放烟雾弹  直到找到他们
We're gonna gas them out floor by floor until we find them.
等一下  如果你要用烟雾弹
Whoa, hold on there, tex. If you use gas you're gonna
你们也什么都看不见  我不能
Compromise visibility ,and I can't afford
再冒险让某个外交官脑袋挨枪子儿了
Another diplomat getting shot in the fez.
我们用的是氯丙烷
We're using chloropropane.
无色  无味
It's colorless, it's odorless.
他们根本不会察觉到自己是怎么中的招
They won't even know what hit them.
大家听好
All right, listen up.
两个人在东边的楼梯井放烟雾
I want two men in the east stairwell with the gas,
两个在西边楼梯底下
Two at the base of the west stairwell
防止他们再往楼下逃
In case they try to come back down again.
我会准备好后援  行了吗
I'll have backup detail ready, all right?
行动  动作快
Let's go, move, move!
莎拉
Sara?
天哪
Oh, my god.
莎拉
Sara.
Sara,
你受伤了吗  你还好吧
You hurt? You okay?
我还好  克里斯蒂娜跑了
I'm fine. Christina's gone.
最下面抽屉里面有刀
There's a knife in the last drawer.
你知道她去哪了吗
Do you have any idea where she went?
不知道
No.
锡拉在她手里
She has Scylla.
她设计陷害了林肯和迈克尔
She set up Linc and Michael.
她可能躲在任何地方
She could be anywhere.
迈克尔和林肯
Michael and Lincoln?
他们现在背上了杀害印度官员的黑锅
Yeah, they were framed for the murder of an Indian official.
他们现在是新闻头条
It's all over the news.
这个克里斯蒂娜的计划
That was Christina's plan, and...
他们现在在哪
Where are they now?
被困在了熊猫湾酒店里
They're trapped at the Panda Bay Hotel.
警察正在找他们
The police are looking for them.
知道了
Okay.
你不能过去
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! You can't go there.
到处都是警察
The cops are everywhere.
你不要拦着我
I really need you to get out of my way
这我办不到
Well, that's not gonna happen.
你不关心我  我也不关心你
You don't care for me, I don't care for you
但是我欠迈克尔的  你逃吧
Much either, but I owe Michael, okay? Run.
他现在正在水深火热之中
He's in a sea of trouble right now.
我不会抛弃他
I'm not abandoning him.
我不是让你抛弃他
I'm not telling you
你什么忙也帮不了
To abandon him. There's nothing you can do for him.
我要是想跑  早就跑了
Listen, I'd run if I could run.
但是我跑的话  他们就会对我老婆下手
But if I run, they go after my wife,
所以我才会再陷泥沼
So I have to jump back in.
你不需要
You don't.
我不会逃避
I'm not running.
我要留在这里
I'll stay here, okay?
这样  迈克尔才会知道我在哪
That way, Michael knows where I am.
克里斯蒂娜也会知道
So does Christina.
如果她想让我死  我早就死了
If she wanted me dead, I would be already.
随便你吧
Suit yourself.
阿历克斯
Alex?
谢谢你
Thanks.
如果你看见迈克尔  告诉他我在这里
And if you see Michael, tell him I'm here.
好的
Yeah.
我明白这对你有多痛苦
I know how difficult this must be for you.
总理先生  我也失去了一个儿子
Mr. Prime Minister, I, too, lost a son
当他还是个孩童的时候
When he was just a child.
你的儿子是被刺客害死的吗
Was your son murdered by an assailant's bullet?
当然不是
Of course not.
有消息说那帮中国人是幕后主使
I've heard the news that the Chinese are behind this.
对  我也听说了
Yes, I've heard that as well.
所以我来这儿了
And that's why I'm here.
不是为了讨论我儿子是怎么死的
Not to discuss how my son died,
而是怎么为他报仇雪恨
But how to avenge him.
你所说的 "技术"
Your technology-- as you put it--
我听说了有关它多种用途的风声
I've heard rumors of its varied applications.
南都  我们稍安勿躁
Nandu, let's take a breath here.
不  我儿子死的那一刻我就无法平静了
No! The time to take a breath expired when my son died.
你儿子和我已经计划把这项技术
Your son and I had planned to use the technology
用于人道主义关怀
For humanitarian endeavors.
我们的目标不是将其用于战争
Warfare applications were not our goal.
但既然它们已经归我了  而且归根结底
But now they are mine, and at the end of the day,
你只是一个做买卖的商人
You're a businesswoman with a product
而我是买家
And I am a buyer.
我要买下你所拥有的全部知识产权
I want to commit to all the intellectual property you possess.
我要中国血债血偿
I want the People's Republic of China To feel the pain I feel right now!
你清楚
Do you comprehend the ramifications
你这项提议的后果吗
Of what it is you're proposing?
比你还清楚
More than you know.
如你所愿
If it is what you want.
我必须得走了
I must go now...
准备付款事宜
To make arrangements for your payment
和我儿子的葬礼
And arrangements for my child's burial.
喂
Yeah?
恭喜啊  你们又出名了
Congratulations. You're famous again.
新闻上全都在说你们杀了另一个甘地
You're all over the news for killing Gandhi.
我也料到会这样
I figured as much.
对啊  情况越来越糟糕了
Yeah, well, it gets worse.
-他们要用烟雾弹逼你们出来  -什么时候
- They're gonna gas you out. - When?
他们已经在行动了  他们在一层层排查
They already started. They're going floor-by-floor.
现在大概已经到达第三或第四层楼了
They're about at the third or fourth floor right now.
你现在为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you just telling me about this now?
我必须要离开门廊
I had to leave the lobby.
我不能再引更多人怀疑了
I can't make anybody more suspicious.
喂  迈克尔  迈克尔
Hello, Michael? Michael?
林肯  我需要你的帮助
Linc, I need your help.
我四年级的时候
When I was in fourth grade,
我猜对了试卷上所有答案  结果得了A
I... I got an A for guessing all the answers on this test.
我从没想过我竟能考这么高
I never thought I'd beat those odds.
什么样的倒霉蛋才会在5年内
What kind of loser gets set up
被陷害参与了两桩举世瞩目的刺杀案呢
For two high-profile assassinations within five years?
林肯  这不是你的错
Linc,this is not your fault.
如果他们当时没得逞的话
If they didn't get away with it then,
他们现在也休想办到
They're not gonna get away with it now.
但是我需要你集中精神
But I need you to focus.
我需要你的帮忙  林肯
I need your help, Linc.
没错  我们走
Right. Let's get out of here.
达林・胡克斯  国土安全局
Darrin Hooks, Homeland Security.
能带我去见你们的主管吗
Can you point me to whoever's in charge here?
国土安全局  你们要派多少人过来啊
Homeland? How many of you guys are they sending here?
赛尔夫探员已经进去了
Agent Self's already inside.
谁
Who?
当・赛尔夫探员
Agent Don Self.
刚刚到这儿了不久
Got here a little while ago.
我是胡克斯
Yeah, it's Hooks.
那个应该在洛杉矶死了的探员的名字
The name of that agent that was supposedly killed recently in L.A.?
是不是  当・赛尔夫
Was his name Don Self?
一切都正中克里斯蒂娜下怀
It's all falling out exactly as Christina planned it.
现在她就要得偿所愿了
Now she's going to have everything she ever hoped for.
她想重燃1962年中印边境之战的战火
She's trying to reignite the 1962 China-India Border War
那次冲突好不容易才和解
Which ended in an uneasy truce
那时两国在边远荒芜的山区相持不下
When neither country could withstand the losses
直到双方两败俱伤才罢休
They were sustaining in those remote and desolate mountains.
如果她成功煽动了另一场战争
If she succeeds in provoking another war,
诬陷是中国方面
And framing China
刺杀了印度总理的儿子
For the killing of India's Prime Minister's son,
那就绝对足够有煽动性的了
It's certainly provocation enough.
她会引发一场会持续数十年的军事冲突
She'll set off a military conflict that will last for decades
有可能永无宁日了
That may never be resolved.
你为什么不自己干
Why didn't you do it yourself?
权力  金钱  似乎是你钟爱的东西
Power, money, seem to be things you love.
因为如果印度牵涉进来  巴基斯坦也会
Because if India's involved, that drags in Pakistan.
然后俄罗斯就要开始防御它的边境了
Then Russia's gonna want to defend its borders.
然后不到一年  整个欧洲都牵扯其中
Then within a year, Europe's in it
接着就是美国
And after that, the United States.
这是一场同归于尽的灾难
It's an apocalypse in which everyone loses!
克里斯蒂娜一直都太自傲
And Christina has always been too prideful
太反复无常  不愿接受这个事实
And too unstable to accept that.
明白了
Got it.
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
你好  我想你能帮忙
Hi. Yes, I think you can.
赛尔夫探员
Agent Self.
唐纳德・赛尔夫
Donald Self?
我是达林・胡克斯探员
Agent Darrin Hooks.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
也很高兴见到你
It's good to see you, too.
站住  别动  别动
Hold it. Hold it right there. Don't move.
你到底在做什么  胡克斯
What the hell are you doing, Hooks?
你总要自相残杀吗
You always pull guns on fellow agents?
对  当一个应该已上西天了的探员
Yeah, when agents that are supposedly dead
和杀他的人出现在同一家宾馆的时候
And are found later in a hotel
我就会那么干
With the guys who kill you
能告诉我你和布鲁斯还有斯科菲尔德
You mind telling me what you're doing here
在这里干吗
With Burrows and Scofield?
我的身份不能暴露
My cover called for me
只能装死  明白吗
To be dead, okay?
人们会理解我们的所作所为的
People were catching on to what we were doing,
我的死让我得以金蝉脱壳
And my death freed me up
但布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德是被陷害的  明白吗
But Burrows and Scofield have been set up, okay?
没有记录显示你在执行秘密任务
There's no record of you in covert ops.
就是这么安排好的
That was by design.
等一切结束了  我们再联系总部
Look, when this is all over, we'll call the home office,
我会输入我的许可代码
I'll punch in my clearance code,
你可以请我喝两杯
You can buy me a couple of drinks,
我俩再分享一下其中的乐趣
And we'll share some laughs about this.
但现在我得完成我的任务
But right now I need to do my damn job.
不行
No.
你跟我走
You're gonna follow
我们现在就把事情弄清楚
And we're gonna clear this up right now.
好  但斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯的事是真的
Okay, but what I said about Scofield and Burrows is true.
他们是被陷害的
They've been set up.
你得调查清楚这件事
You need to look into this.
等我们出去之后
Oh, I'm gonna look into everything
我会把一切都调查清楚
As soon as we get outside.
我们走
Let's go.
你搞定装卸口了吗
Did you clear the loading dock doors?
没有  但是有人做了
No, but someone else did.
什么意思
What do you mean?
有人杀死了警卫
Someone must have taken him out.
也就是说酒店里除了警察
Which means there's someone in the hotel
还有其他人在找你们
Other than the police that's looking for you.
林肯
Linc,
我们得走了
We got to move.
不止有警察在追我们了
Got more than just the cops after us now.
你知道自己在干什么吗
Whoa, whoa. You know what you're doing?
不知道
No.
我们走
Let's go.
哈钦森队长
Captain Hutchinson!
有间房门被打开了16楼
We've got a room breach on 16.
我是哈钦森
This is Hutchinson.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯在16楼
Scofield and Burrows are on 16.
重复  斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯在16楼
I repeat, Scofield and Burrows are on 16.
快  快  快
Go, go, go!
上  上  上
Move, move, move!
这边
This way.
确保门能关紧
Make sure the door can shut.
我们需要足够的压力
We need the pressure to build.
他们来了  他们上来了
They're coming. They're coming!
到达16楼
We're on 16.
收到
Copy that.
听我命令
On my mark.
冲
Go.
赶紧增援
Backup detail!
行动  快  快  快
Move! go, go, go, go!
上  上  上  快点
Move, move, move! go, move!
上  上
Move, move!
发生什么事了
What the hell happened?
他们设了陷阱
They booby-trapped us.
他们上了天台
They made a move for the roof.
好的  带他们去医院
All right, get them to a hospital.
好的  我们走  快  快  快
All right. Let's go! Move, move, move!
站住别动
Stop right there!
布鲁斯  休想动手拿枪
Don't make a move for that weapon, Burrows.
把面罩摘了
Take the masks off.
立刻摘了
Take them off now!
手放到脑后
Hands behind your head.
你们最好祈祷
You'd better pray to god that
我的手下没有出事
My men are found out all right.
不过是个冲击波
It was a concussive blast.
他们只是失去知觉了
They're just unconscious.
闭嘴
Shut up.
放松
Easy!
Easy.
就像他刚说的那样  别想动手拿枪
And I'd follow that advice about not going for your guns.
将军要你们回他办公室一趟
The general would like you back at the office.
就现在
Now.
酒店的事进展顺利吗
Did all go well at the hotel?
我妈妈和莎拉怎么样
What's going on with Sara and my mother?
克里斯蒂娜逃走了
Christina escaped.
莎拉没事
Sara's okay.
她还在公寓里
She's in the condo.
打扰一下  你俩是不是想单独聚一聚
Excuse me, would you boys like a little alone time to catch up?
你究竟想要我们做什么
What exactly do you expect from us?
你们得为自己的过失负责
You need to take responsibility for your failures.
我们没有失手
Hey, we failed nothing.
整件事都是个圈套
This whole thing was a setup.
-你明知道  -林肯・布鲁斯果然聪明
- You know it.  - Lincoln Burrows was outsmarted.
谁能料想到那是陷阱呢
Who could have anticipated that?
你得面对现实  一切都已经结束了
I think you need to accept that this is over.
我手上的筹码握得太久了
I've been holding a chip for far too long.
是时候出手了
It's time to play it.
我们有过君子协议
I made you boys a promise.
你们找回锡拉
You would find Scylla
我给你们一笔钱
And I would see to it you got some cash
并毁掉那份名单
And had the slate wiped clean.
我仍想遵守协议
I intend to keep that promise.
然而  如果遵守了一项协议
However, if I keep one promise,
所有的协议都得遵守
I have to keep them all.
现在
Now...
我想看看
I wonder
谁才是那个大赢家
Who the big winner will be.
-别这么做  -别做什么
- Don't do this.  - Don't do what?
我寄信给你们的时候
When I sent you those envelopes,
并不是跟你们开玩笑
I wasn't just playing games
我说得很清楚
I made it very clear
你们只有一天时间
That you had one day
来完成任务
To accomplish your job,
否则后果自负
Or there would be consequences.
那是什么
What's that?
后果
The consequence.
打电话给我们王后区的手下
Call our man in Queens.
王后区  你打电话到纽约干什么
Queens? What are you calling New York for?
麻烦打开免提
Put it on speaker, please.
-请讲  -对4号目标采取行动
- Yes. - Move on Subject Four.
我就一条街的距离
I'm a block away.
预计两分钟内到达
ETA is less than two minutes.
你个王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
我老婆只是个手无缚鸡之力的女人
My wife is a defenseless woman.
赛尔夫先生没有透露过他有个老婆  是吧
Mr. Self didn't inform you that he had a wife, did he?
换了是我  也不会说的
Well, I wouldn't talk about my wife either
要是我有点喝高了  酒后驾车
if I'd had a few too many Bourbons, got behind the wheel,
不小心就把个绝代佳人碾成了花椰菜
And turned a beautiful young woman into a piece of broccoli.
别伤害她
Don't do anything.
我猜那才是你要携带锡拉潜逃的原因
I assume that is why you tried to run away with Scylla?
辜负了一个福利只够支付你
To screw a government that was giving you benefits
一个小县城环城高速监管费的政府
that would only pay for a county facility overlooking the belt parkway,
你转手卖了锡拉  你和她就可以从此消失
and to sell it so that you and she could disappear
改头换面  永远逍遥快活了
And be hidden forever.
这就是生活[法语]
C'est la vie.
我看到目标了
I have the subject in sights.
她在医院的院子里坐在轮椅上
She's in a wheelchair under a tree in the hospital courtyard.
可以动手了吗
Do I have a go?
求求你别伤害她
Please don't do this.
求你了  你们可以杀我  你们杀我吧
Okay, please, you can kill me, okay, you can kill me
现在就行  求你了  杀我吧
Right now, please, kill me.
你没必要这样  我们会拿到锡拉的
You don't need to do this. We'll get Scylla.
那才是我想听的答案
That's what I wanted to hear.
那是我们正在做的
Well that's what we'r trying to do
-我们快找到了  -但你们必须知道
- We're getting it. - But you have to know what awaits you
如果失败  等待你们和自己爱人的下场
And your loved ones if you don't.
我们都明白
We understand, okay?
-执行命令  -求求你别这样
- Execute the order. - Please don't do it!
天哪
Oh, my god, oh, my god!
救命  救命
Get help, hel--!
我想你刚才请求了死刑
I believe you made a request.
蒂博格  确保他死定了
Bagwell, make sure he's dead.
大家现在都明白了吗
Does everyone understand now?
我们现在可以同心协力了吗
Are we all on the same page?
很好
Good.
开工了  开工了
Let's get down to business.
7.5亿美元
Three-quarters of a billion dollars
在卢森堡  用的是匿名账户
In a numerical account in Luxembourg.
如果你还关心慈善工作的话
If you are still worried about humanitarian efforts,
给联合国儿童基金会写张支票
Write a check to UNICEF.
24小时内所有数据就会送到
All the data will be delivered within 24 hours.
正合我意
That's what I expected.
你的计划非常成功
You played it perfectly.
联系下我们在中国的联系人
Reach out to our contact in China.
我感觉他们可能也会对我们的货很感兴趣
I have a feeling they may be interested in what we're selling as well.
克里斯蒂娜  我不建议
Christina, I don't advise
脚踩两只船
Playing both sides of this coin.
瘦猪有食吃
Pigs get fat
肥猪一刀死
And hogs get slaughtered.
去联系中国的联系人
Reach out to China.
不  让我们的人
No! Keep our people
守好佛罗里达和乔治亚州的每个私人机场
At every private airfield in Florida and in Georgia.
我们不能让克里斯蒂娜离开这个州
We can't have Christina leaving the state.
她在玩弄印度人的感情
She played on India's emotions,
可能说明她想在今天与
Which probably means she'd want to meet
其中一个大使会面
With one of their emissaries today
趁自己还很受欢迎
While they're still running hot.
她可能还在迈阿密
She could still be in Miami,
或许就在大使馆里
Maybe at the embassy.
不  她不会在大使馆的
No. She's not at the embassy.
她和印度做的任何交易
Any deal she makes with India
都会绝对地保密
Will be strictly off the radar.
现在她关心的只有2件事
Right now she's concerned with two things.
一件是将锡拉卖出去
One is closing the deal on Scylla,
我先假定她已经完成了
Which I'm assuming she's already done,
第二件事就是拿到钱
And the second is getting paid.
没有赛尔夫的踪迹
No sign of Self.
卖掉锡拉她能拿到多少钱
How much can she get for Scylla?
印度的5亿美金  还有中国的5亿
Half a billion from India, the same from China.
海外账户
Overseas account?
国外电汇吗
Foreign wire transfer?
我怀疑她不会收普通支票
I doubt she's taking any food stamps.
她会确认
She's going to want confirmation
在她离开美国之前
That that money is safely overseas
那些钱在海外账户是安全的
Before she leaves the U.S.
我们找到那些钱
We find the money,
我们就找到了我母亲
We find my mother.
通常国际电汇的结算
Normally it takes three business days
需要三个工作日
For an international wire transfer to clear,
除非是一家美联储授权的银行
Unless the bank is a Federal Reserve Signatory, in which case
那样的话转账会立即生效
The transfer is immediate.
你觉得她会亲自去银行吗
You think she'll head to the bank?
她只要从买家已经从海外转账过来的
All she has to do is withdraw a few grand from the millions
上百万美元里面取出几千块
That that buyer has probably transferred overseas already.
她就知道了钱全到账了
She'll know it's all there.
那么只要我们找到一家美联储授权的
So let's find a Federal Reserve Signatory bank in Miami.
迈阿密银行  我们就有机会找到她
We'll have a shot at finding her.
还有锡拉
And Scylla.
你瞧  迈克尔  这就是
There, Michael, you see, that's
为什么我刚才没有把你的名字放在碗里
Why I didn't put your name in the bowl.
你是这里唯一无法取代的人
You're the only one here that's irreplaceable.
探员  线人  打手
Agents, informants, muscle--
他们都可胜任  但是...
They're nice to have, but...
他们都是可以取代的
Finally they're replaceable.
附近有家支行  大概20分钟的路程
There's a branch about 20 minutes away.
你的头脑
That mind of yours--
简直是百万里挑一的
It's one in a million.
很高兴看到它终于为我所用了
Nice to see it finally working for me.
我不是为你干的
I do not work for you.
走着瞧
Not yet.
是合法的
It's legitimate,
我向你保证
I assure you.
好的
Oh, okay.
我想取回10000美元现金
I just want to withdraw the $10,000
以确定卢森堡账户是否已准确无误地建好
So I can be sure the Luxembourg account is properly set up.
当然
Of course.
她在里面吗
Is she in there?
是  我从窗子那看见她
Yeah, I saw her through the window.
正和一个高个的黑发男子说话
She's talking to a tall, dark-haired guy.
他们就是在酒店里面陷害我们的人
They're the same guys who set us up at the hotel.
我们等她出来  杀他们个措手不及
We wait until she comes out, just jump them.
那么  我们怎么对付她的保镖呢
So... What do we do about her security?
要想对付她  得先搞定她的保镖
I mean, we jump her, we gotta jump the guys she's with,
天知道  还会有多少探员会像蚂蚁一样
And God knows how many other agents are gonna come crawling
从门外冲进来
Out of the woodwork like ants.
听着  我不想说得这么直白
Look, um... I hate to bring up the obvious,
但是我记得上次  你们俩依然对
But last time I checked, you two still disagreed
锡拉到手后如何处置  各有打算
As to what to do with Scylla If we actually get it.
是啊  我猜就是这样
Yeah, that's what I thought.
别说这烂事了
Well, let's skip the damn thing.
我是说  谁能拦住我们
I mean, who's gonna stop us?
就凭一个17岁的小保安弟弟吗
A 17-year-old security guard?
不是  可能是那个拿枪的家伙
No, probably the guy with the gun.
他一看到我们的脸就会开火
He'll open fire as soon as he sees our faces.
那么  或许可以不让他们看到我们的脸
Then, uh... maybe they shouldn't see our faces.
然后送披萨的来了
So then the pizza guy showed up,
然后韦恩从树丛里跳出来
And Wayne jumped out of the bushes
想要把披萨抢过去  但是...
And tried to grab the pizza, but the...
但是那个家伙...
But the guy...
我的天啊
My god.
你还好吗  先生
Are you okay, Mister?
没事
Yeah.
去打911
Go call 911.
-快去  -别去
- Go, go. - No.
别去  别打给任何人
No, don't call anyone.
行吗
Okay?
别打给任何人
Don't call anybody.
Don't call anyone.
你知道吗  一旦那个弟弟拿到了
You know, once baby brother's got his little hands
你的"魔法盒子"
On that magic box of yours,
他要是想骗过马吉拉大猩猩[指代将军]
I don't think it's going to be too hard for him
简直就是易如反掌
To trick Magilla Gorilla,
你知道我是什么意思吧
If you know what I'm saying.
不  我不知道
No, I don't.
你还真以为
And you really think
斯科菲尔德会不顾他侄子的安危
That Scofield's going to risk his nephew's life?
他把"头等奖"交给"坏人"之前
He's gonna figure out something
肯定会想出点别的坏点子来的
Before he hands first prize over to the bad guys.
斯科菲尔德想得很单纯  就像童子军
Scofield thinks pure, like a little cub scout.
布鲁斯  他的思维也很幼稚
Burrows, he just thinks like a cub.
他说得对
He's right.
斯科菲尔德在外面拿着我想要的东西
I don't feel comfortable having Scofield
而我困在这却没有他的把柄
Out there with something I want
我可不放心
While I'm stuck here with nothing he wants.
我需要筹码
I need leverage.
你看见他们刚过来的时候
You saw the way Mahone pulled Scofield over
马宏把他拉到一边去了吧
When they first got here.
我打赌他们说的肯定是关于
Bet you a wooden nickel they was talking
女医生和她的藏身之处
About little Dr. Underpants and her whereabouts.
但是我们不知道在什么地方
Too bad we don't know where that is.
又错了  卷发小子
Wrong again, curly.
你们都在这嚼口香糖的时候
While everyone was up here flapping their gums,
我擅自跑去了马宏的车上
I took the liberty of toddling down to Mahone's car,
查了他GPS上的最近输入的一个地址
Checking out the last address he put in his GPS.
还有一线希望  找到你想要的筹码
There's a gambler's chance we might find the leverage
就在这个地方
You're looking for right here.
我去办
I'm on it.
不
No.
你想参与行动
You wanted to get in on the action,
机会来了
Here's your chance.
好的  我再帮您点一下
Okay, I'll just count this out for you.
没这个必要
That won't be necessary.
那好吧
All righty.
这是您交易记录的打印凭条
Here's a printed record of your transaction,
我想您的余额还有这么多
And I think a balance that high,
您确定不想和我们的投资顾问谈一谈吗
Are you sure you don't want to talk to one of our investment specialists?
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
所有人  趴下
Everybody down on the ground!
快点  都别动  没人会受伤
Now! Nobody move, Nobody gets hurt.
你  趴下
You, down.
天啊  邪门了
Thanks. What are the odds?
别
Don't.
箱子
The case.
我来拿
I'll take that.
你好  老妈
Hi, mom.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯正从银行出来
Scofield and Burrows leaving the bank, now!
快跑
Go!
拿着锡拉快跑
Take Scylla and go!
我们一起走
We gotta stay together!
说了  快走
I said go!
快
Come on!
他好像没子弹了
I think he's out.
上
Move in.
美国司法系统一开始为无罪释放
How much eggs does the U.S. court system  have on its face
林肯・布鲁斯  花了多大功夫呢
for exonerating Lincoln Burrows in the first place?
功夫不到位  宝拉
An omelet's worth, Paula.
你应该记得我从不赞成无罪释放
If you remember I was never in favor of the exoneration.
林肯・布鲁斯是个给人卖命的暴徒
Lincoln Burrows is a thug for hire,
他弟弟也不是省油的灯
And his little brother is no better.
我惊讶于司法系统就这么忽略了警告
I'm amazed that the court system just glossed over the warning signs.
-举个例子吧  -第一
- Such as?  - For one,
他们绝不该把布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德搅和进来
They should've never let Burrows and Scofield in
他们应该看看斯科菲尔德的过去
They should've looked at Scofield's past.
显然他没有犯罪记录
It's clear that he had no criminal background.
一个杰出的结构工程师干嘛去抢银行
Why would a brilliant structural engineer rob a bank?
也许是要还清他的助学贷款
Maybe he needed to pay off his student loans.
不是钱的原因
It wasn't about the money.
你觉得司法系统
What do you think the judicial system
会从这件事中学到什么
Is going to learn from all this?
法院应该敲响警钟了
This has been a huge wake-up call for the courts.
法官们要搞清楚他生活中的整个关系网
Judges will have to look all the relationships in his life...
放松  小医生  放松
Easy now, doc, easy.
只不过是你友好的邻居蒂博格
It's just your friendly, neighborhood T-Bag.
我现在需要你的合作
Now I'm gonna need your cooperation.
把你那双脏手拿开
Get your hands off me,
婊子...
You son of a...
托你男友的福  我就一只手
Not hands, thanks to your boyfriend.
刚才说过了
Now, as I was saying before,
我需要你的合作
I just need your cooperation.
到这里来
Come in here.
没事了
All right.
他太慢了
He's taking too long.
出事了
Something's wrong.
我们要回去找他
We gotta go back for him.
他说他会赶上来的
He said he'd catch up.
不对  出事了
No, something's wrong.
打给他
Call him.
迈克尔
Michael,
我们现在得到它了
Now that we have this,
要怎么处理它呢
What the hell are we going to do with it?
他不接
He's not answering.
林肯
Linc?
我在广播里听说了银行抢劫事件
I heard about the bank robbery on the radio.
你们兄弟俩可真喜欢上镜头啊
You boys just can't stand to be out of the news, can you?
我猜你们拿到锡拉了吧
I assume you've got Scylla?
快了
We're getting close.
有消息会通知你
We'll keep you posted.
如果我是你  现在不会挂电话  小子
I wouldn't hang up just yet if I were you, son.
迈克尔  我们在公寓里
Michael, we're in the apartment.
我知道它在你手上
I know you have it.
不然  克里斯蒂娜也不会冒险公然火拼
Otherwise, Christina would never have risked a public shootout.
现在 事情很简单
Now, I'm going to make this easy for you,
把锡拉给我
Bring me Scylla,
不然的话  莎拉这回就真的要上西天了
Or this time, Sara's death will not be faked.
怎么回事
What is it?
莎拉在将军手上
The General has Sarah.
拿去吧
Take it.
我发誓  如果你敢动她一根汗毛
I swear if you touch her...
你好  儿子
Hello, son.
我想你有件我想要的东西
I believe you have something I want.
而我也有你想要的东西
And I have something you want--
尽管我无法理解其中原因
Although I'll never really understand why.
好吧
All right,
也许我们能想出什么办法
Maybe we can work something out.
我给过你机会想办法
I gave you the opportunity to work something out.
是你拒绝了我  迈克尔
You rejected me, Michael.
听着  我们见面谈吧
Look, let's meet and talk about this.
没门  谈话的机会
No, the time for talking
在你套上滑雪面具的那一刻就没有了
Passed about the time you put those ski masks on,
不是吗
Don't you think?
迈克尔  现在我要做的是
So, here's what I'm going to do, Michael.
对林肯的右胸腔开枪
I'm going to shoot Lincoln through the right rib cage,
子弹就擦过他右肺的下面
Just grazing the lower quadrant of his right lung.
右肺会慢慢地衰竭
It will slowly collapse,
呼吸会非常困难
Making it very difficult to breathe.
如果5小时内  他不接受治疗
If he doesn't get medical attention, within five hours,
就必死无疑
He'll be dead.
克里斯蒂娜  妈妈  别
Christina... mom... please
林肯
Linc!
时间不多了  迈克尔
Second hand's spinning, Michael.
看来你该做抉择了
Looks like you have a little decision to make.
要锡拉
Scylla
还是要你爱的人
Or someone you love.